Guide to the UNITE Local 169 Amalgamated Northeast Regional Joint Board Memorabilia Banners
UNITE Local 169 Amalgamated Northeast Regional Joint Board Memorabilia Banners
Kheel Center for Labor-Management Documentation and Archives, Cornell University Library
UNITE Local 169 Amalgamated Northeast Regional Joint Board Memorabilia Banners,
6000/016 MB
Union of Needletrades, Industrial and Textile Employees (UNITE); UNITE Local 169
20 linear ft.
Banners.
Kheel Center for Labor-Management Documentation and Archives, Cornell University Library
SUBJECTS
Names:
Union of Needletrades, Industrial, and Textile Employees.; Amalgamated Clothing and Textile Workers Union --Archives; International Ladies' Garment Workers' Union --Archives; International Ladies' Garment Workers' Union. Joint Board (Cleveland, (Ohio))-- Archives; International Ladies' Garment Workers' Union. Knitgoods Council (Cleveland, (Ohio)) -- Archives; International Ladies' Garment Workers' Union. Northeast Department--Archives; International Ladies' Garment Workers' Union. Cotton Garment & Miscellaneous Trades Department--Archives; International Ladies' Garment Workers' Union. Local 26 (Cleveland, (Ohio))--Archives; Union of Needletrades, Industrial, and Textile Employees --Archives; Union of Needletrades, Industrial, and Textile Employees. Local 169 (New York, N.Y); UNITE HERE (Organization) --Archives
Subjects:
Textile workers--Labor unions; Clothing workers--Labor unions
Form and Genre Terms:
Banners.
INFORMATION FOR USERS
Access Restrictions:
Access to the collections in the Kheel Center is restricted. Please contact a reference archivist for access to these materials.
RELATED MATERIALS
Related Collections:
5619/014: ACWA Local 169 Files
6000/016: UNITE Local 169 Files
6000/016 P: UNITE Local 169 Amalgamated Northeast Regional Joint Board Photographs
6200/001: UNITE HERE Local 169 Files
CONTAINER LIST
- Vote for Peter Vallone for Governor Chuck Schumer for US Senate Working Family Party Carl For State Comptroller (Box 1.1)
  Colored tape letters on black nylon, some letters peeling and cracking, light surface dirt, deep folds; 83L x 58W; photo no. 6491-6495; a copy of the photo is with the banner roll in the stacks
- Local ACTWU 169 (Box 1.2)
  White polyester or cotton? with red and blue painted letters, some surface dirt; 61Lx78.5W; photo no. 6496-6498; a copy of the photo is with the roll in the stacks
- Amalgamated Northeast Region Joint Board Local 169 UNITE! (Box 2)
  Gray shades on nylon with reinforced holes for air flow; 116L x80W; photo no. 6488-6490; a copy of the photos are with the roll in the stacks
- Cotton Garment and Misc. Trades Dept. [Eagle above chain in circle around nested chevrons and stars] ILGWU Est. Sept. 1935 (Box 3)
  Maroon satin? banner with yellow braid, yellow stitched letters fringe on bottom and edge of over skirt, hanging loops. Satin front and back, good condition; 43Lx30.5W; photo no. 6499-6504, 6537-6554; a copy of photo is with roll in stacks
- Northeast [map and compass motif Organized 1935] Department ILGWU - AFL (Box 3.2)
  Blue satin? banner with gold chain-stitched letters. Gold braid around edges, fringe on top and bottom edges, 3 tassels, hanging loops. Appliqu in center w/frayed edges, decorative design center bottom; 57Lx39W; photo no. 6505-6513, 6524-6537; a copy of the photo is with the roll in the stacks
- International Ladies Garment Workers Union [Circle with General Executive Board Union Made with Eagle label] Local 26 Cloakmakers Union International Ladies [clasped hands] Garment Workers Cleveland, Ohio. Org. June 15. 1909. (Box 3.3)
  Orange (faded?) satin? banner with metal hanging rings, braid around edges, fringe at bottom. Union label at top with white decorative swishes. Union label and clasped hands hand stitched? Rest machine stitched letters; 56Lx40W; photo no. 6556-6561; a copy of the photo is with the roll in the stacks
- International Ladies Garment Workers Union [Circle with General Executive Board Union Made with Eagle label] Local 26 Cloakmakers Union International Ladies [clasped hands] Garment Workers Cleveland, Ohio. Org. June 15. 1909. (Box 3.3)
  Orange (faded?) satin? banner with metal hanging rings, braid around edges, fringe at bottom. Union label at top with white decorative swishes. Union label and clasped hands hand stitched? Rest machine stitched letters; 56Lx40W; photo no. 6556-6561; a copy of photo with roll in the stacks
- International Ladies Garment Workers Union [Circle with General Executive Board Union Made with Eagle label] Knitgoods Council International Ladies [clasped hands] Garment Workers Cleveland, Ohio Org. July 1, 1941 (Box 3.4)
  Blue nylon banner with gold braid fringe at each edge and hanging sleeve, fringe at bottom. Union label and clasped hands machine chain stitch. White and red flourishes, gold metallic braid on overskirt edge. Union; 56Lx40W; photo no. 6562-6569; a copy of the photo is in the box with the banner
- International Ladies Garment Workers Union [Circle with General Executive Board Union Made with Eagle label] Joint Board International Ladies [clasped hands] Garment Workers Cleveland, Ohio Org. July 21, 1911 (Box 3.5)
  Navy/purple nylon with appliqué hand embroidered Union label at top, machine sewn white flourishes at top, machine stitched gold letters outlined in red and graphics, gold braid along edges, metal? Trim on edge of overskirt, some with red pattern sewing over it. Fringe at bottom, hanging rings at top. Moderate surface dirt; 56Lx39W; photo no. 6570-6580; a copy of the photo is with the item in the stacks
- Amalgamated Northeast Region Joint Board Local 169 UNITE! (Box 4)
  Various blue white and red, nylon banner, large center circle carries design, reinforced holes for air flow. Dirty, moldy, set folds; 115Lx93W; 6514-6519; a copy of the photo is with the roll in the stacks.